Privacy policy

Effective on: 18 September 2020. This Privacy Policy completely replaces the previous

version.

OWOX is committed to protecting your safety and privacy, and takes its responsibilitiesregarding the security of information very seriously.This privacy policy explains what data OWOX collects about you, how and why OWOXuses it, who OWOX discloses it to, and how OWOX protects your privacy.If you do not agree to this Privacy policy, please do not use our website and our services.

1\. Who is collecting and/or processing your data?

OWOX, Inc., a company established under the laws of California, United States ofAmerica, with registration number C3725260, (referred to as “OWOX”, “we”, “us”, “our” in thisPrivacy Policy) is a company that collects and/or processes your data.

Data controller. OWOX collects some personal data from you, for example when you use

OWOX website, provide feedback on OWOX services or contact OWOX. In this case, OWOXis the data controller for purposes of European data protection legislation and OWOX takes onthe obligations and responsibilities of data controllers, particularly described in General DataProtection Regulation.

Data processor. You may decide to transfer OWOX with your clients’ personal data by

using our services. In this case, you are the data controller and OWOX stands out as the dataprocessor for purposes of European data protection legislation and OWOX takes on theobligations and responsibilities of data processor, particularly described in General DataProtection Regulation.

2\. What personal data OWOX collects and processes?

The term “personal data” in this Privacy Policy is the information that relates to you andallows OWOX to identify you, either directly or in combination with other information thatOWOX may hold. Your personal data may include for example your name, your contact details(email, telephone number), your payment details or information on how you use our website.The personal data you provide us with is only processed and used in the manner adequatefor the purpose for which it was collected. OWOX does not combine personal data that wasobtained for a variety of purposes.When providing the personal data through OWOX website, you consent to the OWOXusage of provided data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and/or any additional agreementbetween you and OWOX.OWOX may collect and process the following categories of information about you:

Your contact details (name, surname,

telephone number, email, company name,

company website)

When you log in or create an account or

project in OWOX services

When you choose an offer OWOX makes

available on its website

When you request an OWOX services

demonstration or trial

When you subscribe for OWOX newsletters

When you register for OWOX webinars

When you send a request for OWOX

technical support

When you send a request for third-party

services information (e.g. Google Analytics

360)

Your payment details (credit card number,

expiry date, etc.)

When you purchase OWOX products or

services

When you validate your payment details

Your IP, cookies When you visit our website

When you use our services

The communications you exchange with

OWOX (for example, your emails, letters,

calls, or your messages on OWOX online chat

service)

When you contact OWOX or you are

contacted by OWOX messages on our online

chat service)

Your posts and messages on social media

directed to OWOX

When you interact with OWOX on social

media

Your feedback When you reply to our requests for feedback

or participate in our surveys

Information about how you use our website When you navigate on our website

Aggregated data statistics (for personalization

of user experience in services)

When you provide your access to Google

Analytics account

By using our services, you may be providing us with your clients’ personal data. Youshould therefore ensure that you have collected your clients’ respective consents and approval inorder to process their data in accordance with applicable data protection law and the Terms ofuse. We shall be entitled to: obtain, collect, distribute, record, organise, adapt or alter, retrieve,consult, align, combine, transfer, use, store, block, destroy, and conduct the international transfer(including countries that do not ensure adequate level of protection of personal data) of thepersonal data you provide us with. Your clients’ personal data belongs to you and OWOX willfollow your instructions in the regard of your client’s personal data. It will be stored at GoogleBigQuery tables and at your Google Cloud Platform project.

We do not knowingly collect personal data from children under 16 without the consent ofparents or legal guardians. You must be of age of majority in your jurisdiction to use our websiteor services. If you are under the age of 16, you may only use our website with the permission ofyour parents or legal guardian.We do not knowingly collect personal data revealing racial or ethnic origin, politicalopinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, and genetic data, orbiometric data data concerning health or data concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexualorientation.

2\. Rights of data subjects

You have certain legal rights to access certain personal data we hold about you and toobtain its correction, amendment, portability or deletion.

You may exercise those rights in your account, in the “Settings” chapter, or by contactingus via data-protection@owox.com. We will respond to your request at the soonest, but in anycase within 30 calendar days from the date we receive your request.According to California Consumer Protection Act, consumers from California has thefollowing rights:- Right to request from OWOX:(1) The categories of personal data that OWOX has collected about you,(2) Categories of sources from which personal data are collected,(3) Business or commercial purpose for the collection or sale of personal data,(4) Categories of third parties to whom OWOX provides personal data,(5) Categories of your personal data that has been sold, and categories of third parties towhom personal data has been sold,(6) The specific personal data that OWOX has collected about you,You can exercise this right by using the method described above.- The right to non-discrimination in the event you exercise your rights under the CaliforniaConsumer Privacy Act.

4\. How and why OWOX uses your data?

We use your personal data for the following purposes:

4.1. To provide our services to you and technical support

OWOX uses your information to perform OWOX services in relation to your project. Forexample, to automatically import data into your Google Analytics account, collect GoogleAnalytics unsampled data in your Google BigQuery project, store frequently used queries forGoogle BigQuery, make transactions, or when you ask for the technical assistance.

4.2. To communicate with you and manage our relationship with you

When you provide your details to submit the request for information on our website,download any material or presentation from our website, request a demo of our services, registerfor webinar, start a trial or services usage, contacted us on social media, or in any other wayexpress your interest in our services and products, we will communicate with you to respond onyour request and subscribe you to our newsletter. You may unsubscribe from us or request tostop any communication with you by clicking the "unsubscribe" link on our email or by replying"unsubscribe" for any emails from our sales or marketing team (if "unsubscribe" link isunavailable). We will honor your request.Occasionally we may need to contact you by email and/or telephone for administrative oroperational reasons, for example in order to send you the confirmation regarding webinarregistration, the reply for your request on the technical assistance, to remind you about trailexpiry date or pending invoices.Please be aware that these communications are not made for marketing purposes and assuch, you will continue to receive them even if you opt-out from receiving marketingcommunications.

4.3. To personalize and improve your customer experience

OWOX may use your personal data in order to tailor our services to your needs andpreferences and to provide you with a personalised customer experience.OWOX may also collect information on how you use our website, which pages of ourwebsite you visit most, what products you buy, in order to understand what you like. OWOXmay use this information to tailor the content and offers that you see on our website and, if youhave agreed to receiving marketing communications, to send you relevant messages that wethink you like.

4.4. To inform you about our news and offers that you may like

OWOX may send you marketing communications, if you have indicated your interest inour product and services: submitted the request for information on our website, downloaded anymaterial or presentation from our website, requested a demo of our services, registered forwebinar, started a trial or services usage, contacted us on social media, or in any other wayexpressed your interest in our services and products..Please note that OWOX does not share your contact details and other personal data withother companies for marketing purposes, unless OWOX has obtained your consent to do so.If you do not want to receive marketing communications from us, you can at any time optout from receiving marketing communications by updating your account settings or by clickingon the relevant "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any email you received from us, or byreplying "unsubscribe" for any emails from our sales or marketing team (if "unsubscribe" link isunavailable).

4.5. To improve our services, fulfil our administrative purposes and protect our business

interests and for marketing purposes

The business purposes for which OWOX will use your information include lead'sevaluation, marketing among leads and customers, accounting, billing and audit, credit or otherpayment card verification, fraud screening, safety, security and legal purposes, systems testing,maintenance and development.OWOX may use anonymous data, which will not include personally identifiableinformation or information that identifies or would reasonably be expected to identify you, tocollect the OWOX service statistics and to improve and enhance the OWOX services (the data iscollected in anonymized form, e.g. in the form of derived metrics and coefficients).

4.6. To showcase the results of using OWOX services or your feedback, only upon prioragreement with you and to the agreed extent4.7. To comply with our legal obligations and compliance reasons, such as theprevention, detection, or investigation of a crime; loss prevention; or fraud.

OWOX may also use personal information to meet its internal and external auditrequirements, information security purposes, and as OWOX otherwise believe to be necessary orappropriate: (a) under applicable law, which may include laws outside your country of residence;(b) to respond to requests from courts, law enforcement agencies, regulatory agencies, and otherpublic and government authorities, which may include such authorities outside your country ofresidence; (c) to enforce our terms and conditions; and (d) to protect our rights, privacy, safety,or property, or those of other persons, court order, law or governmental request.

We use your personal data based on:your consent,

agreement concluded with you, or to take action at your request before concluding anagreement,compliance with our legal obligations,based on our legitimate interests, for example, when we use cookies on our website orwhen we receive your data from advertising campaigns, from open public sources or as a resultof communications with you.

5\. Security of your data

We are committed to taking appropriate technical and organisational measures to protectyour personal data against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss,destruction or damage to personal data.Your personal information is stored behind secured networks and is only accessible by alimited number of people who have special access rights to such systems, and are required tokeep the information confidential. In addition, all information you supply is encrypted usingSecure Socket Layer (SSL).Our services use official APIs from Google, Bing, Facebook, Yandex, Vkontakte andothers, where it is technically applicable to access the data that you provide.To provide access to Google services, we use OAuth authentication. This is an openauthorization protocol, which provides us with limited access to protected resources for ourservices without passing your data for authorization in your account.You can limit access to your data in your Google account settings at any time.We will protect your data in the following ways:using cryptography, where necessary;using password, where necessary; andrestricting access to your data (i.e. access to your personal data is granted only to those ofour employees or contractors for whom the access is necessary).

6\. International transfer of data

6.1. As described in this Privacy Policy, OWOX may in some instances disclose yourpersonal data to third parties. Where OWOX discloses your personal data to a third party,we require that the third party has appropriate technical and organisational measures inplace to protect your personal data.6.2. The information that you provide to us will be held in our systems, which are located onour premises or those of an appointed third party.6.3. We and some of our subprocessors are based outside the EEA. That is why your personaldata may be accessed by and processed outside the European Economic Area,Switzerland and/or United Kingdom.6.4. When we act as data controller, the transfer of personal data outside the EEA,Switzerland and/or United Kingdom is based on this Privacy Policy. In this case, wecheck if there is a European authorities decision that the third country, a territory or oneor more specified sectors within that third country, or the international organisation inquestion ensures an adequate level of protection, and/or in the absence of this decision wewill rely on one or more of the appropriate safeguards, referred to in Article 46 of theGDPR.

6.5. When you are (a) an EU-based controller (or a processor for an EU-based controller), (b)OWOX is engaged as a processor (or a subprocessor), (c) the conditions set forth underArticle 3 of the GDPR are met, and (d) only to the extent that any processing of personaldata by OWOX takes place in any country outside the EU (except if the country ensuresan adequate level of protection as defined in Article 45 of the GDPR), the parties agreethat the Standard Contractual Clauses, attached as annex to this Privacy Policy, will applyin respect to that processing, and OWOX will comply with the obligations of the ‘dataimporter’ and you will comply with the obligations of the 'data exporter'.6.6. The following additional conditions shall apply during the international transfer ofpersonal data (hereinafter — Client's Personal data) based on the Standard ContractualClauses:6.6.1. Legal basis. If you provide us with Client's Personal Data, you should complywith the applicable EU data protection laws and regulations. As between theparties, OWOX is responsible for the lawfulness of the processing of Client'sPersonal Data in its capacity as a processor (or subprocessor), and you areresponsible for the processing of Client's Personal Data in your capacity as acontroller (or a processor for an EU-based controller).6.6.2. Subprocessor's engagement. You provide OWOX with the authorization toengage sub-processors for processing of Client's Personal Data, including transferto third country or an international organization, provided the provisions ofStandard Contractual Clauses are fulfilled. OWOX hereby confirms that itrequires all of its personnel and engaged subcontractors authorized to processClient's Personal Data to commit themselves to confidentiality, or ensures thatthey are under an appropriate statutory obligation of confidentiality, and not toprocess Client's Personal Data for purposes other than as described in this PrivacyPolicy. This authorization should be considered as a "prior written consent" asprescribed by Clause 11 of the Standard Contractual Clauses.6.6.3. Integration with Third Party services. OWOX may provide links to integrationswith Third Parties services, including, without limitation, certain Third Partyservices, which may be integrated directly into OWOX Services. If you elect toenable, access or use such Third Party Services, the access and use of such ThirdParty services is governed solely by the terms and conditions and privacy policiesof such Third Party services, and OWOX does not endorse, is not responsible ornot liable for, and makes no representations as to any aspect of such Third Partyservices, including without limitation their consent or the manner in which theyhandle Client's Personal Data or any interaction between you and the provider ofsuch Third Party services. The provider of Third Party services shall not bedeemed subprocessors for any purpose under this Privacy Policy.6.6.4. International Transfer. You acknowledge that OWOX and its subprocessors maymaintain data processing operations in countries that are outside of the EEA,Switzerland and the UK.

1.1.1. Limitation of Liability. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary, will either party of thisPrivacy Policy, their affiliates, officers, directors, employees, agents, service providers,suppliers or licensors be liable to the other party or any third party for any lost profits,

lost sales, lost data (being data lost in the course of transmission via Your system or overthe internet through no fault of OWOX), loss of goodwill, or for any type of indirect,incidental loss or damages, incurred by the other party in connection with this PrivacyPolicy. For the avoidance of doubt, this provision shall not be construed as limiting theliability of either party with respect to claims brought by data subjects.

7\. Term for data storage

OWOX will not store your personal data for longer than is necessary for the purpose forwhich it was provided or collected. OWOX will only retain the personal data that serves alegitimate purpose (e.g. applicable legal regulations may require the retention of data, or somedata may be necessary for the purposes of billing outstanding amounts).After 2 years from the moment of last visit of OWOX website, your account and yourunsubscription from OWOX newsletters, OWOX at its sole discretion delete your personal dataor anonymize it.OWOX will also delete your personal data within 30 calendar days upon receiving yourrequest for data erasure.OWOX reserves its right to retain a part of personal data, which are required by applicablelaw and for the term, required by applicable law (e.g. applicable law may require that somepersonal data shall be retained for tax accounting or for issues of the invoice for unpaid fees).

8\. Sharing your personal data

OWOX uses a limited number of third party providers to assist us in providing the servicesto our customers. Third parties may access, process or store personal data in the framework andupon our instructions only. OWOX may share your information with the following persons:

Affiliates. OWOX may disclose your information to its affiliates or subsidiaries, whichmay use your information to provide services to you or to communicate with you regardingservices provision on OWOX behalf.

Service Providers. OWOX may disclose the information it collects from you to third party

vendors, service providers, contractors or agents who perform functions on OWOX behalf.

Other Third Parties. OWOX may disclose your information to third parties upon your

instructions to do so. For example, when you ask OWOX to transfer the data from your CRM toyour Google BigQuery project.

Credit and debit card companies. OWOX may disclose your payment details strictly to the

companies that process the card payments for the purposes of processing of payment for OWOXservices.

Business Transfers. If OWOX is acquired by or merged with another company, if

substantially all of OWOX assets are transferred to another company, or as part of a bankruptcyproceeding, OWOX may transfer the information it has collected from you to this company.

9\. Cookies or other tracking technologies

In order to improve our services, to provide you with more relevant content and to analysehow visitors use our website, or for direct marketing purposes, we may use technologies, such ascookies, local storage and pixels. Please be aware that in most cases we will not be able toidentify you from the information we collect using these technologies.

For example, we use software to monitor customer traffic patterns and website usage tohelp us develop the design and layout of the website in order to enhance the experience of thevisitors to our website. In addition, in order to understand how our customers interact with theemails and the content that we send, we use pixels that allow us to know if the emails we sendare opened.We use cookies and local storage on our website. These technologies are small pieces ofinformation stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. On your further visits to thatwebsite, the information stored in the cookie is sent back to the website. This allows the websiteto recognise you and tailor its content to your needs.

What cookies does OWOX use?

We use the following types of cookies:(i) essential cookies, which are essential for the provision of access to our websites andServices;(ii) functionality cookies, which are used to personalize the content in accordance withyour actions on our website;(iii) performance cookies, which do not identify you individually (until you enter youridentification details in any of our forms) but help us to evaluate the website performance and itsstatistics; and(iv) targeting/advertising cookies, which help advertise OWOX offers and services on theother sites.We also use analytics and similar services that collect third-party cookies:1\. Google Analytics, Google Optimize, and Google AdWords (Google Privacy Policy isavailable at https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en, text and URL may be changedby Google sole discretion),2. Intercom (Intercom Privacy Policy is available athttps://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy, text and URL may be changed byIntercom sole discretion),3. Facebook (Facebook Privacy Policy is available athttps://www.facebook.com/policy.php, text and URL may be changed by Facebook solediscretion),4\. Twitter (Twitter Privacy Policy is available at https://twitter.com/en/privacy, text andURL may be changed by Twitter sole discretion),5. LinkedIn (LinkedIn Privacy Policy is available athttps://www.linkedin.com/legal/preview/privacy-policy, text and URL may be changed byLinkedIn sole discretion).6. Yandex.Metrics (Yandex Privacy Policy is available athttps://yandex.ru/support/legal/confidential/index.html?lang=en, text and URL may be changedat Yandex sole discretion),7\. AdMixer (AdMixer Privacy Policy is available at https://sales.admixer.ua/privacy, textand URL may be changed by AdMixer sole discretion),8. Zendesk (Zendesk Privacy Policy is available athttps://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/, text and URL may bechanged by Zendesk sole discretion),

9. Albacross (Albacross Privacy Policy is available athttps://albacross.com/privacy-policy/, text and URL may be changed by Albacross solediscretion),10\. Other services.

How to reject or delete cookies?

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. However, you do not have to acceptcookies and you can, should you choose to at any time, reject or block the use of cookies anddelete all cookies currently stored on your device. You can find out how to do this for yourparticular browser by clicking “help” on your browser’s menu, or by visiting:www.allaboutcookies.org, http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices,http://optout.networkadvertising.org/.However, if you turn off cookies, the functionality of our Services may be limited (i.e. inthe case of essential cookies you may not be able to access our websites, your account andservices).

10\. Links

OWOX websites may contain links to others websites, which are owned and operatedindependently of OWOX. Therefore, any information you provide to those websites will begoverned by their own privacy policy principles and data collection practices. OWOX assumesno responsibility or liability for information handling procedures and/or policies of suchindependent websites.

11\. Revisions

OWOX may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time, without the advancenotice and any modifications are effective when they are posted at our website.OWOX may make changes to this Privacy Policy including as part of the new Europeandata protection legislation which will start to apply on 25 May 2018 (the “General DataProtection Regulation”) and Privacy Shield program.

12\. Privacy Shield notice12.1. OWOX complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S.

Privacy Shield Frameworks (referred to as “Privacy Shield”) as set forth by the U.S. Departmentof Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferredfrom the European Union and/or the United Kingdom and/or Switzerland to the United States.OWOX has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy ShieldPrinciples. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy ShieldPrinciples, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shieldprogram, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.

12.1. Questions or Complaints You may direct any questions or complaints concerning

our Privacy Shield compliance to data-protection@owox.com or at our mailing address: 340 SLemon Ave Ste 2021 Walnut CA 91789 United States.

We will respond to you to resolve your issue as soon as possible but in any event within 30days from receiving your letter.

12.2 Dispute Resolution If you have not received timely response to your concern, or we

have not addressed your concern to your satisfaction, you may seek further assistance, at no costto you, from EU Data Protection Authorities for EU/EEA/UK Data Subjects (available athttp://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm), and theSwiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner for Swiss Data Subjects (availableat https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/task.html), which are an independentdispute resolution bodies.

12.3. Arbitration You may also be able to invoke binding arbitration for unresolved

complaints but prior to initiating such arbitration, a resident of a European country participatingin the Privacy Shield must first: (1) contact us and afford us the opportunity to resolve the issue;(2) seek assistance from EU Data Protection Authorities for EU/EEA/UK Data Subjects, and theSwiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner for Swiss Data Subjects; and (3)contact the U.S. Department of Commerce (either directly or through a European Data ProtectionAuthority) and afford the Department of Commerce time to attempt to resolve the issue. If such aresident invokes binding arbitration, each party shall be responsible for its own attorney’s fees.Please be advised that, pursuant to the Privacy Shield, the arbitrator(s) may only imposeindividual-specific, non-monetary, equitable relief necessary to remedy any violation of thePrivacy Shield Principles with respect to the resident.

U.S. Federal Trade Commission Enforcement Our Privacy Shield compliance is subject

to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

13\. Contact information

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and shouldbe addressed to data-protection@owox.com.You may also send your request to our data protection officer – Maksym Voloshyn, email:data-protection@owox.com.For EU and EEA citizens — you may also contact our EU Data Representative: OWOXlimited, Boumpoulinas 11, 1st floor, 1060 Nicosia Cyprus.

Statement for the performance of California Consumer Protection Act:

Effective from 01 January 2020

Based on Article 1278.130 California Consumer Protection Act we inform you on the followingactions, performed in the past 12 months:1. OWOX collected the following categories of personal data: personal data, listed inparagraph 2 of OWOX Inc Privacy Policy,2. OWOX did not sell personal data to third parties,3. OWOX disclosed for a business purposes to its contractors and processors: personal data,listed in paragraph 2 of OWOX Inc Privacy Policy.

Standard Contractual Clauses (processors)

for the purposes of Article 26(2) of Directive 95/46/EC for the transfer of personal data to processorsestablished in third countries which do not ensure an adequate level of data protection

Name of the data exporting organisation: You, when You act as an EU-based Controller (or aProcessor for an EU-based Controller) (the data exporter)

And

Name of the data importing organisation: OWOX, Inc., with its registered office at Suite 340 S

Lemon Ave Ste 2021 Walnut CA 91789 United States, (the data importer), each a “party”; together

“the parties”,

HAVE AGREED on the following Contractual Clauses (the Clauses) in order to adduce adequatesafeguards with respect to the protection of privacy and fundamental rights and freedoms of individualsfor the transfer by the data exporter to the data importer of the personal data specified in Appendix:

Clause 1. Definitions

For the purposes of the Clauses:

(a) 'personal data', 'special categories of data', 'process/processing', 'controller','processor', 'data subject' and 'supervisory authority' shall have the same meaning as in

Directive 95/46/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 24 October 1995on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data and onthe free movement of such data;(b) 'the data exporter' means the controller or processor who transfers the personal data;(c) 'the data importer' means the processor who agrees to receive from the data exporter

personal data intended for processing on his behalf after the transfer in accordance withhis instructions and the terms of the Clauses and who is not subject to a third country'ssystem ensuring adequate protection within the meaning of Article 25(1) ofDirective 95/46/EC;(d) 'the subprocessor' means any processor engaged by the data importer or by any other

subprocessor of the data importer who agrees to receive from the data importer or fromany other subprocessor of the data importer personal data exclusively intended forprocessing activities to be carried out on behalf of the data exporter after the transfer inaccordance with his instructions, the terms of the Clauses and the terms of the writtensubcontract;(e) 'the applicable data protection law' means the legislation protecting the fundamental

rights and freedoms of individuals and, in particular, their right to privacy with respectto the processing of personal data applicable to a data controller in the Member State inwhich the data exporter is established;(f) 'technical and organisational security measures' means those measures aimed at

protecting personal data against accidental or unlawful destruction or accidental loss,alteration, unauthorised disclosure or access, in particular where the processing involvesthe transmission of data over a network, and against all other unlawful forms ofprocessing.

Clause 2. Details of the transfer

The details of the transfer and in particular the special categories of personal data whereapplicable are specified in Appendix 1 which forms an integral part of the Clauses.

Clause 3. Third-party beneficiary clause

1. The data subject can enforce against the data exporter this Clause, Clause 4(b) to (i),Clause 5(a) to (e), and (g) to (j), Clause 6(1) and (2), Clause 7, Clause 8(2), and Clauses9 to 12 as third-party beneficiary.2. The data subject can enforce against the data importer this Clause, Clause 5(a) to (e)and (g), Clause 6, Clause 7, Clause 8(2), and Clauses 9 to 12, in cases where the dataexporter has factually disappeared or has ceased to exist in law unless any successorentity has assumed the entire legal obligations of the data exporter by contract or byoperation of law, as a result of which it takes on the rights and obligations of the dataexporter, in which case the data subject can enforce them against such entity.3. The data subject can enforce against the subprocessor this Clause, Clause 5(a) to (e) and(g), Clause 6, Clause 7, Clause 8(2), and Clauses 9 to 12, in cases where both the dataexporter and the data importer have factually disappeared or ceased to exist in law orhave become insolvent, unless any successor entity has assumed the entire legalobligations of the data exporter by contract or by operation of law as a result of which ittakes on the rights and obligations of the data exporter, in which case the data subjectcan enforce them against such entity. Such third-party liability of the subprocessor shallbe limited to its own processing operations under the Clauses.4. The parties do not object to a data subject being represented by an association or otherbody if the data subject so expressly wishes and if permitted by national law.

Clause 4. Obligations of the data exporter

The data exporter agrees and warrants:

(a) that the processing, including the transfer itself, of the personal data has been and willcontinue to be carried out in accordance with the relevant provisions of the applicabledata protection law (and, where applicable, has been notified to the relevant authoritiesof the Member State where the data exporter is established) and does not violate therelevant provisions of that State;(b) that it has instructed and throughout the duration of the personal data processingservices will instruct the data importer to process the personal data transferred only onthe data exporter's behalf and in accordance with the applicable data protection law andthe Clauses;(c) that the data importer will provide sufficient guarantees in respect of the technical andorganisational security measures specified in Appendix 2 to this contract;(d) that after assessment of the requirements of the applicable data protection law, thesecurity measures are appropriate to protect personal data against accidental or unlawfuldestruction or accidental loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure or access, in particularwhere the processing involves the transmission of data over a network, and against allother unlawful forms of processing, and that these measures ensure a level of securityappropriate to the risks presented by the processing and the nature of the data to beprotected having regard to the state of the art and the cost of their implementation;(e) that it will ensure compliance with the security measures;(f) that, if the transfer involves special categories of data, the data subject has beeninformed or will be informed before, or as soon as possible after, the transfer that itsdata could be transmitted to a third country not providing adequate protection within themeaning of Directive 95/46/EC;(g) to forward any notification received from the data importer or any subprocessorpursuant to Clause 5(b) and Clause 8(3) to the data protection supervisory authority ifthe data exporter decides to continue the transfer or to lift the suspension;(h) to make available to the data subjects upon request a copy of the Clauses, with theexception of Appendix 2, and a summary description of the security measures, as well

as a copy of any contract for subprocessing services which has to be made inaccordance with the Clauses, unless the Clauses or the contract contain commercialinformation, in which case it may remove such commercial information;(i) that, in the event of subprocessing, the processing activity is carried out in accordancewith Clause 11 by a subprocessor providing at least the same level of protection for thepersonal data and the rights of data subject as the data importer under the Clauses; and(j) that it will ensure compliance with Clause 4(a) to (i).

Clause 5. Obligations of the data importer

The data importer agrees and warrants:(a) to process the personal data only on behalf of the data exporter and in compliance withits instructions and the Clauses; if it cannot provide such compliance for whateverreasons, it agrees to inform promptly the data exporter of its inability to comply, inwhich case the data exporter is entitled to suspend the transfer of data and/or terminatethe contract;(b) that it has no reason to believe that the legislation applicable to it prevents it fromfulfilling the instructions received from the data exporter and its obligations under thecontract and that in the event of a change in this legislation which is likely to have asubstantial adverse effect on the warranties and obligations provided by the Clauses, itwill promptly notify the change to the data exporter as soon as it is aware, in which casethe data exporter is entitled to suspend the transfer of data and/or terminate the contract;(c) that it has implemented the technical and organisational security measures specified inAppendix 2 before processing the personal data transferred;(d) that it will promptly notify the data exporter about:(i) any legally binding request for disclosure of the personal data by a lawenforcement authority unless otherwise prohibited, such as a prohibition undercriminal law to preserve the confidentiality of a law enforcement investigation,(ii) any accidental or unauthorised access, and(iii) any request received directly from the data subjects without responding to thatrequest, unless it has been otherwise authorised to do so;(e) to deal promptly and properly with all inquiries from the data exporter relating to itsprocessing of the personal data subject to the transfer and to abide by the advice of thesupervisory authority with regard to the processing of the data transferred;(f) at the request of the data exporter to submit its data processing facilities for audit of theprocessing activities covered by the Clauses which shall be carried out by the dataexporter or an inspection body composed of independent members and in possession ofthe required professional qualifications bound by a duty of confidentiality, selected bythe data exporter, where applicable, in agreement with the supervisory authority;

(g) to make available to the data subject upon request a copy of the Clauses, or any existingcontract for subprocessing, unless the Clauses or contract contain commercialinformation, in which case it may remove such commercial information, with theexception of Appendix 2 which shall be replaced by a summary description of thesecurity measures in those cases where the data subject is unable to obtain a copy fromthe data exporter;(h) that, in the event of subprocessing, it has previously informed the data exporter andobtained its prior written consent;(i) that the processing services by the subprocessor will be carried out in accordance withClause 11;(j) to send promptly a copy of any subprocessor agreement it concludes under the Clausesto the data exporter.

Clause 6. Liability

1. The parties agree that any data subject, who has suffered damage as a result of anybreach of the obligations referred to in Clause 3 or in Clause 11 by any party orsubprocessor is entitled to receive compensation from the data exporter for the damagesuffered.2. If a data subject is not able to bring a claim for compensation in accordance withparagraph 1 against the data exporter, arising out of a breach by the data importer or hissubprocessor of any of their obligations referred to in Clause 3 or in Clause 11, becausethe data exporter has factually disappeared or ceased to exist in law or has becomeinsolvent, the data importer agrees that the data subject may issue a claim against thedata importer as if it were the data exporter, unless any successor entity has assumed theentire legal obligations of the data exporter by contract of by operation of law, in whichcase the data subject can enforce its rights against such entity.The data importer may not rely on a breach by a subprocessor of its obligations in orderto avoid its own liabilities.3. If a data subject is not able to bring a claim against the data exporter or the dataimporter referred to in paragraphs 1 and 2, arising out of a breach by the subprocessorof any of their obligations referred to in Clause 3 or in Clause 11 because both the dataexporter and the data importer have factually disappeared or ceased to exist in law orhave become insolvent, the subprocessor agrees that the data subject may issue a claimagainst the data subprocessor with regard to its own processing operations under theClauses as if it were the data exporter or the data importer, unless any successor entityhas assumed the entire legal obligations of the data exporter or data importer by contractor by operation of law, in which case the data subject can enforce its rights against suchentity. The liability of the subprocessor shall be limited to its own processing operationsunder the Clauses.

Clause 7. Mediation and jurisdiction

1. The data importer agrees that if the data subject invokes against it third-partybeneficiary rights and/or claims compensation for damages under the Clauses, the dataimporter will accept the decision of the data subject:(a) to refer the dispute to mediation, by an independent person or, where applicable,by the supervisory authority;(b) to refer the dispute to the courts in the Member State in which the data exporter isestablished.2. The parties agree that the choice made by the data subject will not prejudice itssubstantive or procedural rights to seek remedies in accordance with other provisions ofnational or international law.

Clause 8. Cooperation with supervisory authorities

1. The data exporter agrees to deposit a copy of this contract with the supervisoryauthority if it so requests or if such deposit is required under the applicable dataprotection law.2. The parties agree that the supervisory authority has the right to conduct an audit of thedata importer, and of any subprocessor, which has the same scope and is subject to thesame conditions as would apply to an audit of the data exporter under the applicabledata protection law.3. The data importer shall promptly inform the data exporter about the existence oflegislation applicable to it or any subprocessor preventing the conduct of an audit of thedata importer, or any subprocessor, pursuant to paragraph 2. In such a case the dataexporter shall be entitled to take the measures foreseen in Clause 5 (b).

Clause 9. Governing Law

The Clauses shall be governed by the law of the Member State in which the data exporter isestablished.

Clause 10. Variation of the contract

The parties undertake not to vary or modify the Clauses. This does not preclude the parties fromadding clauses on business related issues where required as long as they do not contradict theClause.

Clause 11. Subprocessing

1. The data importer shall not subcontract any of its processing operations performed onbehalf of the data exporter under the Clauses without the prior written consent of thedata exporter. Where the data importer subcontracts its obligations under the Clauses,with the consent of the data exporter, it shall do so only by way of a written agreementwith the subprocessor which imposes the same obligations on the subprocessor as areimposed on the data importer under the Clauses. Where the subprocessor fails to fulfilits data protection obligations under such written agreement the data importer shallremain fully liable to the data exporter for the performance of the subprocessor'sobligations under such agreement.2. The prior written contract between the data importer and the subprocessor shall alsoprovide for a third-party beneficiary clause as laid down in Clause 3 for cases where thedata subject is not able to bring the claim for compensation referred to in paragraph 1 ofClause 6 against the data exporter or the data importer because they have factuallydisappeared or have ceased to exist in law or have become insolvent and no successorentity has assumed the entire legal obligations of the data exporter or data importer bycontract or by operation of law. Such third-party liability of the subprocessor shall belimited to its own processing operations under the Clauses.3. The provisions relating to data protection aspects for subprocessing of the contractreferred to in paragraph 1 shall be governed by the law of the Member State in whichthe data exporter is established.4. The data exporter shall keep a list of subprocessing agreements concluded under theClauses and notified by the data importer pursuant to Clause 5 (j), which shall beupdated at least once a year. The list shall be available to the data exporter's dataprotection supervisory authority.

Clause 12. Obligation after the termination of personal data processing services

1. The parties agree that on the termination of the provision of data processing services,the data importer and the subprocessor shall, at the choice of the data exporter, return allthe personal data transferred and the copies thereof to the data exporter or shall destroyall the personal data and certify to the data exporter that it has done so, unlesslegislation imposed upon the data importer prevents it from returning or destroying allor part of the personal data transferred. In that case, the data importer warrants that itwill guarantee the confidentiality of the personal data transferred and will not activelyprocess the personal data transferred anymore.2. The data importer and the subprocessor warrant that upon request of the data exporterand/or of the supervisory authority, it will submit its data processing facilities for anaudit of the measures referred to in paragraph 1.

Appendix 1 to the Standard Contractual Clauses

Data exporter is: providing personal data to the data importer necessary for the provision ofservices by the data importer to the data exporter.

Data importer is: processing personal data of the data exporter in accordance with theinstructions of the data exporter in order to deliver services to the data exporter.

Data subjects

The personal data transferred concern the following categories of data subjects: Natural personsemployed or otherwise engaged by the data exporter, customers of the data exporter andother users of data exporter products or services, employees of the data exporter

Categories of data

The personal data transferred concern the following categories of data: Names, email address,phone number, username, cookies, IP address, first name, last name, subscriptioninformation.

Special categories of data (if appropriate)

The personal data transferred concern the following special categories of data (please specify):

N/A

Processing operations

The personal data transferred will be subject to activities necessary to provide the data exporterwith products and services, such as: collection; recording; organisation; structuring; storage;adaptation or alteration; retrieval; consultation; use; disclosure by transmission; dissemination orotherwise making available; alignment or combination; restriction; erasure or destruction.

Appendix 2 to the Standard Contractual Clauses

Description of the technical and organisational security measures implemented by the dataimporter in accordance with Clauses 4(d) and 5(c) (or document/legislation attached):Data importer shall implement technical and organisational measures specified in Privacy Policy.
